# Doru-Petru Barbu

curriculum vitae

I'm a seasoned programmer with more than a decade of comprehensive experience in all facets of the software development lifecycle. From the initial analysis to the post-release support phase, I have contributed to the success of projects delivered to more than 20 satisfied customers across 14 European and Asian countries.

#### contact details

Email db@0db.ro

Github https://github.com/fragilematter

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/doru-barbu

## work experience

#### **Senior Software Developer**

2016-12 - present

Bell Gateway SRL

Took over and led the development of a logistics suite<sup>1</sup> for vehicle transportation, stocking and maintenance comprised of a web portal and mobile applications. Led the effort to rebase the project from a custom legacy framework to Laravel with no downtime, from the initial concept to the development roadmap and the implementation; designed and documented new REST APIs replacing the existing SOAP implementation. Participated in the analysis, deployment and start-up of the full software suite, either on-premises or remotely. Performed server and hosting infrastructure administration.

## **Software Developer**

2012-12 - 2016-12

Gateway Software SRL

Full-stack development<sup>2</sup> of a large scale SCM system designed for passenger vehicle configuration, ordering, tracking, and sale to dealers. Participated in requirement analysis and design, extended the integration with the supplier and sales software ecosystems. Wrote specifications, technical documentation, quotes and planned the development of software solutions. Maintained legacy Visual Basic 6 and ASP software solutions.

#### **Software Developer**

2010-12 - 2012-12

Expert Software Company SRL

Participated in the development, continuous updating, deployment and support of a fully featured accounting software suite<sup>3</sup> used by large and small businesses. Led the analysis and development effort for a logistics solution targeted at TL and LTL shipping, featuring driver and truck/trailer management, load-unload planning, weight/volume/floor space tracking, automated driver SMS notifications, refueling data import. Developed custom made-to-order software, ranging from ERP solutions, timesheet tracking integrated with access control, stock management systems integrated with industrial weighing scales. Provided hardware, software and networking troubleshooting.

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup>PHP, Laravel, MSSQL

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>2</sup>.Net WinForms + DevExpress, ASP.NET, MSSQL

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>3</sup>Visual FoxPro, MSSQL/MySql

#### Linux News Editor in English

2009-07 - 2010-01

SoftNews NET (Softpedia)

Tracked events in the IT/Linux area of interest and wrote articles, reviews and tutorials on open source software <sup>4</sup>. Maintained and expanded a database of open source software, including download links, changelogs, short descriptions and screenshots. Translated news pieces from English to Romanian <sup>5</sup>.

IT Tech 2007-09 – 2008-09

"Gheorghe Lazăr" National College

Provided hardware maintenance and troubleshooting, networking, software solution support. Performed setup of video and sound infrastructure for events.

#### education

#### **BSc.** Informatics

2007 - 2010

Spiru Haret University

Courses regarding statistical and numerical analysis, computer architecture, networking, sequential and programmable automata, software engineering and high level programming.

## skills

Languages Bash, C/C++, C#/VB.Net, CSS3, HTML5, Java, Lua, PHP, SQL, Javascript

Instruments DevExpress, Github/Gitlab, Kendo UI, Laravel

Abilities Software Development, Database Design, System Administration, API De-

sign, Security Best Practices

### references

Available upon request

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>4</sup>https://news.softpedia.com/editors/browse/doru-barbu

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>5</sup>Softpedia Forum Translations Archive